Educational Technology Services Records UA245
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
- Great Courses, 2014 -- 2017; UA245.001; 626 Digital Object(s); 1 Web sites
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 2., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.257
    Synopsis: The Problem Addressed by the Vortex Theory -- The Basic Picture of the Vortex Theory -- The Sun, the Planets, and their Satellites -- The Physics of Curvilinear Motion -- The Underlying Physics of Orbital Motion -- The Physics of Light and Its Transmission -- Explanations of Other Cosmological Phenomena -- Subsequent Variations of the Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 3 - Part 4., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.258
    Synopsis: The Sun, the Planets, and their Satellites -- The Physics of Curvilinear Motion -- The Underlying Physics of Orbital MotionThe Physics of Light and Its Transmission -- Explanations of Other Cosmological Phenomena -- Subsequent Variations of the Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 3 - 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 5., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.259
    Synopsis: Descartes' Vortex Account of the Tides -- A Candidate for the Underlying Physics -- An Attempt to End the Issue of Copernicanism -- A New Fundamental Question About Planetary Motion -- The Implicit Challenge to Kepler's "Laws" Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 6 - Part 7., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.260
    Synopsis: The Sun, the Planets, and their Satellites -- The Physics of Curvilinear Motion -- The Underlying Physics of Orbital Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 6 - 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 8., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.261
    Synopsis: A New Fundamental Question About Planetary Motion -- The Implicit Challenge to Kepler's "Laws" -- A New Set of Basic Questions for Cosmology -- A New Evidential Standard in Physical Astronomy -- Cartesian Conceptions of Empirical Science. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 9., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.262
    Synopsis: Descartes' Vortex Account of the Tides -- A Candidate for the Underlying Physics. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 10., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.263
    Synopsis: Descartes' Conception of the Problem -- How To Do Science: the Cartesian Solution -- Empirical Dimensions of Cartesian Science -- The Two Senses of 'Theory' in Science. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 10.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 11 - Part 12., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.264
    Synopsis: Descartes' Conception of the Problem -- How To Do Science: the Cartesian Solution. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 11 - 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 13., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.265
    Synopsis: Descartes' Conception of the Problem -- How To Do Science: the Cartesian Solution -- Empirical Dimensions of Cartesian Science -- The Two Senses of 'Theory' in Science -- Grounds for Objecting to Cartesian Science -- Why Cartesian Science was so Well-Received -- 1651: A Transition into "Modern" Science. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 9 -- Descartes' Principia: The Vortex Theory of the Heavens -- Part 14., 2014-10-28; gc.phil167.266
    Synopsis: 1651: A Transition into "Modern" Science. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 1, Part 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Complete., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.267
    Synopsis: Science in the Thirty Years after Galileo's Death -- Huygens on Motion Under Perfectly Elastic Impact -- Huygens on Circular Motion and Centrifugal Force -- Huygens on the Center of Oscillation: Real Pendulums -- "Rational Mechanics": in the Tradition of Huygens. Section: Class 10, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 1 - Part 3., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.268
    Synopsis: The Development of Astronomy: 1642-1672 -- Post-Galilean Developments in Mechanics -- Christiaan Huygens (1629-1695): a chronology until 1673 -- Huygens and the Measurement of g (1659) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 1 - 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 4 - Part 5., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.269
    Synopsis: Huygens and the Measurement of g (1659) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 4 - 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 6., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.270
    Synopsis: Huygens on Motion Under Perfectly Elastic Impact: Hypotheses Underlying the Initial Theory -- The Initial Theory: Relative Motion Results. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 7., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.271
    Synopsis: Huygens on Motion Under Perfectly Elastic Impact: Hypotheses Underlying the Initial TheoryThe Initial Theory: Relative Motion Results. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 8., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.272
    Synopsis: The Initial Theory: Relative Motion Results -- Toward the Extended Theory: Proposition VIII -- The Extended Theory and its Consequences -- Empirical Evidence for the Two Theories -- Huygens on Circular Motion and Centrifugal Force: The Basic Conceptualization of the Problem. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 9., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.273
    Synopsis: Huygens on Circular Motion and Centrifugal Force: The Basic Conceptualization of the Problem -- The Basic Results and their Significance -- A Theory of the Circular Conical Pendulum -- Comparing Centrifugal Forces with Gravity -- Empirical Evidence for the Overall Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 10., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.274
    Synopsis: Empirical Evidence for the Overall Theory -- Background: Ideal versus Real Pendulums. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 10.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 11., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.275
    Synopsis: Empirical Evidence for the Overall Theory -- Background: Ideal versus Real Pendulums. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 12., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.276
    Synopsis: Background: Ideal versus Real Pendulums -- The Compound Pendulum and its Significance. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 13 - Part 14., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.277
    Synopsis: The Compound Pendulum and its Significance -- The Results on the Center of Oscillation -- The Theory of the Physical Pendulum. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 13 - 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 10 -- Huygens and the Beginnings of Rational Mechanics -- Part 15., 2014-11-04; gc.phil167.278
    Synopsis: Leibniz versus Descartes on Conservation Laws -- The Approach to Science Exemplified by Huygens -- The Emergence of Theoretical Physics as a Subfield -- Huygens and the Continental Tradition in Mechanics. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 10, Part 15.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Complete., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.279
    Synopsis: A New "Post-Galilean" Generation of Scientists -- Astronomy from 1642-1660: Revisitations -- Astronomy in a New Context: (1650s-1670s) -- A New Standard in Astronomy: 1670 to 1684 -- Astronomy 70 Year After Kepler's Astronomia Nova. Section: Class 11, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 1., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.280
    Synopsis: "Forty Years that Shook Science" -- The Legacy of Descartes' Principia -- The New Generation: Huygens among Others -- Boulliau's Geometrical Orbital Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 1.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 2., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.281
    Synopsis: Boulliau's Geometrical Orbital Theory -- Other Alternatives to Kepler's Orbits -- The Development of the Pendulum Clock. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 3., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.282
    Synopsis: The Development of the Pendulum Clock -- Advances in the Astronomical Telescope -- Huygens's Systema Saturnium (1659) -- Cassini on the Sun and on Jupiter and its Satellites. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 4., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.283
    Synopsis: Cassini on the Sun and on Jupiter and its Satellites -- Streete's Astronomia Carolina (1661) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 5., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.284
    Synopsis: Streete's Astronomia Carolina (1661) -- The Founding of the Royal Society (1660-63) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 6., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.285
    Synopsis: Streete's Astronomia Carolina (1661) -- The Founding of the Royal Society (1660-63) Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 7., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.286
    Synopsis: The Founding of the Royal Society (1660-63) -- The Royal Academy of the Sciences (1666) -- New Standards in Experimentation: Hooke -- Post-Cartesian Efforts in Celestial Physics -- Steps Toward a Resolution in Orbital Theory -- The Royal Academy's Expedition to Cayenne. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 8., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.287
    Synopsis: New Standards in Experimentation: Hooke -- Post-Cartesian Efforts in Celestial Physics. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 9., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.288
    Synopsis: The Royal Academy of the Sciences (1666) -- New Standards in Experimentation: Hooke. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 10., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.289
    Synopsis: The Royal Academy's Expedition to Cayenne -- Newton on Refraction: the Newtonian Reflector. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 10.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 11., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.290
    Synopsis: Newton on Refraction: the Newtonian Reflector -- Flamsteed and the Greenwich Observatory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 12., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.291
    Synopsis: Observational Anomalies: The Speed of Light -- Mathematical Astronomy at the End of the 1670s. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 13., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.292
    Synopsis: Flamsteed and the Greenwich Observatory -- Changing Attitudes in Observational Astronomy -- Observational Anomalies: The Speed of Light. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 11 -- Other Developments in Astronomy from 1642 to 1684 -- Part 14 - Part 15., 2014-11-18; gc.phil167.293
    Synopsis: Mathematical Astronomy at the End of the 1670s -- The Underdetermination of Theory by Data -- Emerging Interest in Inverse-Square Forces. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 11, Part 14 - 15.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Complete., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.294
    Synopsis: Background: Newton in the 1660s and 1670s -- Newton's Laws of Motion (vs. Descartes, Huygens) -- Newton on Circular Motion (vs. Descartes, Huygens) -- Newton on Motion along a Cycloid (versus Huygens) -- Newton's Fragment on Hydrostatics (vs. Descartes) Section: Class 12, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 1., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.295
    Synopsis: Huygens and the Science of Mechanics -- Issue: What Difference Did Newton Make? -- Newton: A Biographical Sketch (to 1679) -- Newton's Work in Mathematics: 1664-1680. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 1.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 2., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.296
    Synopsis: Newton: A Biographical Sketch (to 1679) -- Newton's Work in Mathematics: 1664-1680. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 3., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.297
    Synopsis: Newton's Work in Mathematics: 1664-1680 -- Newton's Work in Optics: 1665-1680. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 4., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.298
    Synopsis: Newton's Work in Mathematics: 1664-1680 -- Newton's Work in Optics: 1665-1680. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 4.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 5 - Part 6., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.299
    Synopsis: Newton's Work in Optics: 1665-1680 -- Newton's Early Laws of Motion (vs. Descartes, Huygens): Newton's Conceptualization of the Problem. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 5 - 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 7., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.300
    Synopsis: Newton's Early Laws of Motion (vs. Descartes, Huygens): Newton's Conceptualization of the Problem -- The Principles Governing Angular Motion -- The General Laws of Reflection on Impact. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 8., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.301
    Synopsis: Newton's Results Contrasted with Huygens's -- Newton's Reservations about the Potential for Evidence -- Newton on Circular Motion (vs. Descartes, Huygens): Basic Theoretical Results, versus Huygens's. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 9., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.302
    Synopsis: Newton on Circular Motion (vs. Descartes, Huygens): Basic Theoretical Results, versus Huygens's -- Four Immediate Applications of the Theory -- Newton's Preoccupation: Copernican Concerns -- Universal Gravitation: The Historical Issue. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 10., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.303
    Synopsis: Four Immediate Applications of the Theory. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 10.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 11., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.304
    Synopsis: Four Immediate Applications of the Theory -- Newton's Preoccupation: Copernican Concerns -- Universal Gravitation: The Historical Issue -- The Implicit Conception of Empirical Science -- Newton's Two Part Proof of Isochronism. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 12., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.305
    Synopsis: Newton's Two Part Proof of Isochronism -- The Relationship to the Theory of Free Fall -- Newton's Analysis Contrasted With Huygens's -- Background: the Anti-Cartesian Introduction. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 12 -- Newton's Early Unpublished Work in Mechanics -- Part 13., 2014-11-25; gc.phil167.306
    Synopsis: Background: the Anti-Cartesian Introduction -- Newton's Early Views on Space and Motion -- Newton's Early Conception of Forces -- Newton's Orientation: Copernican Concerns. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 12, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Complete., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.307
    Synopsis: Background to De Motu Corporum in Gyrum -- Three Fundamental Initial Discoveries -- The Results of Keplerian Elliptical Orbits -- Some Extended Results on Galilean Motion -- The Significance of De Motu Corporum in Gyrum. Section: Class 13, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 1 - Part 2., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.308
    Synopsis: Newton's Work in Mechanics Before De Motu -- The Correspondence with Hooke in Late 1679 -- The Comet(s) of 1680-81. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 1 - 2.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 3., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.309
    Synopsis: The Comet(s) of 1680-81 -- The Renewal of Interest in 1684: Halley. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 3.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 4 - Part 5., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.310
    Synopsis: The Comet(s) of 1680-81 -- The Renewal of Interest in 1684: Halley. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 4 - 5.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 6., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.311
    Synopsis: The Renewal of Interest in 1684: Halley -- The Conceptual Shift to Centripetal Forces -- Three Fundamental Initial Discoveries: Preliminaries: Definitions and Hypotheses. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 6.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 7., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.312
    Synopsis: Theorem 1: Kepler's Area Rule -- The First Key -- Theorem 2: Forces in Uniform Circular Motion -- Theorem 3: Force Variation along Arbitrary Trajectories: The Fundamental Enabling Result -- Problems 1 & 2: Two Applications of Theorem 3. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 7.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 8., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.313
    Synopsis: Three Fundamental Initial Discoveries: Preliminaries: Definitions and Hypotheses -- Theorem 1: Kepler's Area Rule -- The First Key -- Theorem 2: Forces in Uniform Circular Motion -- Theorem 3: Force Variation along Arbitrary Trajectories: The Fundamental Enabling Result -- Problems 1 & 2: Two Applications of Theorem 3. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 8.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 9., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.314
    Synopsis: Problems 1 & 2: Two Applications of Theorem 3 -- Problem 3: The Inverse-Square Rule of Force. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 9.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 10 - Part 11., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.315
    Synopsis: Problem 3: The Inverse-Square Rule of Force -- Theorem 4: The Keplerian 3/2 Power Rule. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 10 - 11.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 12., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.316
    Synopsis: Problem 3: The Inverse-Square Rule of Force -- Theorem 4: The Keplerian 3/2 Power Rule. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 12.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 13., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.317
    Synopsis: Theorem 4: The Keplerian 3/2 Power Rule -- Scholium: Determining the Orbits of Planets -- Problem 4: Determining Inverse-Square Trajectories -- Problem 5: Vertical Fall Under Inverse-Square Gravity. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 13.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 14., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.318
    Synopsis: Problem 5: Vertical Fall Under Inverse-Square Gravity -- The Moon Test Repeated in 1684: Confirmation -- Problems 6 and 7: Resistance and Galilean Motion. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 14.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 15., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.319
    Synopsis: Problems 6 and 7: Resistance and Galilean Motion -- Scholium: Resistance and Projectile Motion -- Advances Made by Version 1 of De Motu. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 15.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 13 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum in Gyrum (i.e. Version 1) -- Part 16., 2014-12-02; gc.phil167.320
    Synopsis: Advances Made by Version 1 of De Motu -- A "Galilean-Huygensian" Theory of Orbital Motion -- Departures from Galilean-Huygensian Science -- Loose Ends in Version 1 of De Motu -- Version 1 of De Motu Versus the Principia. Generally corresponds to the video segment: Class 13, Part 16.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 14 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum, Version 3 -- Complete., 2014-12-09; gc.phil167.321
    Synopsis: De Motu Corporum in Gyrum, Version 1 -- De Motu, Version 3 (the "Augmented" Version): New Peliminaries -- De Motu, Version 3 (the "Augmented" Version): Two Extended Scholia -- In the Aftermath of De Motu, Version 3 -- Toward an Emerging Conception of Science. Section: Class 14, Complete.
  - Notes to Philosophy 167: Class 14 -- Newton's De Motu Corporum, Version 3 -- Part 1., 2014-12-09; gc.phil167.322